Adventure has a new destination.
Sahara is a action, adventure, comedy film directed by Breck Eisner.
Seasoned adventurer and treasure hunter Dirk Pitt, a former Navy SEAL, sets out for the African desert with his wisecracking buddy Al in search of a
confederate ironclad battleship rumored to have vanished long ago, the main draw being the treasure supposedly hidden within the lost vessel.
When the daring duo come across Dr.
Eva Rojas, a beautiful scientist who is juggling an escape from a warlord and a mission to
stop the spread of a powerful plague, their desert expedition begins to heat up.
Dirk Pitt, played by Matthew McConaughey.
Dr. Eva Rojas, played by Penélope Cruz.
Al Giordino, played by Steve Zahn.
General Zateb Kazim, played by Lennie James.
Yves Massarde, played by Lambert Wilson.
Admiral Jim Sandecker, played by William H. Macy.
Sahara is a 2005 action-adventure film directed by Breck Eisner based on the
best-selling 1992 novel of the same name by Clive Cussler.
It stars Matthew McConaughey, Steve Zahn and Penélope Cruz, and follows a treasure hunter who partners
with a WHO doctor to find a lost American Civil War Ironclad warship in the Sahara Desert.
The film was shot in 2003 on-location in Morocco
as well as in the United Kingdom.
It became notable for its many production issues, including doubling its production
budget from $80 million to $160 million and a series of lawsuits.
Sahara grossed $119 million worldwide at the box-office, ultimately failing to recoup all of its
costs, and is often listed among the biggest box-office failures of all time.
The film explores themes of dying and death, civil war,
based on novel or book, africa, warlord.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional and mind_bending.